# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# **IRFAN ALI BAIG**

#19, 4th crs, Gandhi nagar, K.G. Halli,

near K.G.N public school. Bangalore -560045, India Mobile: +91-8971233463.

Email: irfanalibaig27@gmail.com

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Driven and results-oriented Accounts Receivable Executive with an aim to perfect my duties to be able to effectively contribute to the financial success of the organization using my applied knowledge in accounting, bookkeeping principles and accounts receivable procedures.

# SUMMARY/OVERVIEW

I am a hard-working professional accountant with extensive knowledge and experience of accounts receivable procedures and policies.

I am an energetic and dedicated team player and I pride myself on my accuracy, Professionalism and ability to meet deadlines. I would love nothing better than a stimulating position where I can apply my skills and expertise across different areas of accounting.

#### **EDUCATION**

SSLC - KSEEB PUC - Pre University BBM- Bangalore University

#### PROFESSIONAL COURSE

Certified Revenue Cycle Specialist(CRCS) – Professional.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- · MS Word.
- Excel.
- · Outlook.
- PowerPoint.
- Excellent spelling and grammar skills.

#### **SKILLS**

- Exceptional Management Expertise Admirable Communication Skills
- Excellent Organizational Skills Creative in Problem Solving & Conflict Resolution
- Outstanding Leadership Talent
- Efficient execution of administrative paperwork
- Strong familiarity with payroll procedures and policies

- Great knowledge in word processing
- Vast knowledge in account balancing and reconciliation
- Open Office, Word, Spreadsheet.

### **KEY SKILLS**

- Typing speed of 60 words per minute
- Capability to meet deadlines and work under pressure
- · Ability to work with minimal supervision
- Excellent command over English Language
- Knowledge in using Word and Excel.
- Ability to quickly learn new software packages
- · Discretion and understanding of the need for confidentiality
- Perfectionist attitude with attention to accuracy
- Above average planning and organization skills

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Organizational and planning skills.
- · High Confidentiality.
- Communication skills.
- Data collection and management.
- Attention to detail.
- · Problem-solving.
- Initiative.
- Integrity.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

**Organization:** OMEGA HEALTH CARE PVT LIMITED – Bangalore.

**Company Profile:** Omega Healthcare is one of the premier offshore providers of medical coding, billing, accounts receivable management, claims processing, and healthcare revenue management. Omega Healthcare is dedicated to providing the following services to our clients:

- Medical Coding Professional and Facility
- Data Entry into Software and Practice Management Systems Charges, Coding, Demographics and Cash/Payment Posting
- Accounts Receivable Management Analysis and Collections (Physician and Hospital Claims)

Omega Healthcare has extensive experience in providing services in a variety of hospital-based and office-based physician specialties. We also have experience in providing services to A/R Management companies and their hospital clients for their credit balance account, regular accounts receivable and facility coding needs. Our delivery organization is driven by quality and Six Sigma methodologies, which ensure improved processes and client satisfaction.

Duration: From March 2013 - October 2014.

**Designation: ACCOUNTS RECEIVABLE EXECUTIVE** 

**Organization:** ACS A Xerox Company Pvt Ltd- Bangalore

**Duration: From October 2014 – December 2015** 

**Designation: S.R ACCOUNTS RECEIVABLE EXECUTIVE** 

Organization: Pradot Technologies Pvt Ltd- Bangalore

**Duration: From February 2016 – July 2016 Designation: S.R Reimbursement Specialist-2** 

Organization: LogixHealth Solutions Pvt Ltd- Bangalore

**Duration: From August 2016 – Present** 

**Designation: S.R Provider Reimbursement Specialist-Auditing** 

# **Accounts Receivables**

Accounts Receivables, one of the most prominent departments in a billing company that is dedicated to collect the revenue from the insurance carrier.

# Roles & Responsibilities

- Complete account reconciliations and process adjustments
- Perform billing, payment allocation, collection and activity reporting following established protocols, to tight deadlines
- Maintain up-to-date billing system and customer files
- Monitor customer account details and identify and investigate non-payments, delayed payments and other irregularities
- · Organize recovery system and initiate collection efforts
- Investigate and resolve customer queries
- · Monitored and collected overdue customer fees
- Maintained inventory
- Prepared financial statements such as budgets, billing and cost reports
- Maintained and updated fee status of clients
- Performed data entry and entered bills and vouchers
- Verify that transactions comply with financial policies and procedures.
- Prepare, verify, and process invoices and coding payment documents.
- Prepare batches of invoices for data entry.
- Data enter invoices for payment.
- Record all cheques and post payments.
- Prepare vendor cheques for mailing.
- Maintain listing of accounts receivable and payable.
- Issues and maintains Certificates of Insurance for the company.
- Greet and assist visitors.
- · Answers multi line phones.
- Direct calls and respond to inquiries.
- Receiving and organizing and coding incoming mail.

- Managed financial departments with responsibility for Budgets, Forecasting, Payroll, Accounts Payable and Receivable.
- Worked closely with employers regarding late payments.
- Improved quality by updating and maintaining the Titan system.
- Managed and coordinated all activities of the Accounts Receivable / Collection departments.
- $\bullet$  Implemented new procedures to increase the progress and efficiency of AR/AP departments.
- Verified, allocated and posted all payments and details of business transactions to accounts.
- · Reconciled and balanced accounts.
- Compiled reports to show statistics, such as cash receipts, accounts payable and receivable, etc.

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Investigated suspicious vouchers and discovered misappropriated funds, for which I was rewarded with a pay rise.

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 21- April -1991. Father's Name: Khuddus Ali Baig.

Sex: Male.

Nationality : Indian. Religion : Islam.

Marital Status: Unmarried.

#### LANGUAGES KNOWN

Fluency in reading, writing & speaking: English & Hindi Fluency in speaking: English, , Hindi, Urdu.

REFERENCES
Gladly Provided Upon Request
(IRFAN ALI BAIG)

Date: 14/11/2017 Place: Bangalore